Matheus Coelho

Software Engineer

Email: matheusvieiracoelho@gmail.com Portfolio: http://matheuseabra.me

GitHub: https://github.com/matheuseabra

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/matheus-seabra-080ab3b7

PERSONAL STATEMENT

As a Software Engineer with over 5 years writing code for client and server web applications, I had the privilege of working with small-to-medium software engineering teams, helping to build products that are fast, scalable and maintainable, while meeting user's needs and business requirements.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

At FineTune

March 2019 - Present

FineTune is a startup in the EdTech Industry, creating cloud-based solutions for benchmark and formative writing assessments in grades 6-12 that seamlessly integrates high-quality content, automated feedback, hybrid (A.I./human) rubric-based evaluation, and detailed reporting to inform instruction, tighten the feedback loop, and measure student performance over time.

- Working with the product team, stakeholders and clients, helping to deliver the vision for their main product FineTune Writing, scaling the product up to millions of students on the U.S.
- Responsible for feature development from initial concept to production with JavaScript and Python, also working with quality assurance engineers in order to ensure acceptance criteria for features were being met.
- Led a high risk/reward test end-to-end automation implementation with Cypress.
- Mentored and onboarded new engineers regarding development and business processes.
- Facilitated SCRUM daily meetings such as daily standups and retrospectives.
- Technologies/tools: ReactJS, Django, PostgreSQL, GraphQL, Docker, CircleCl, AWS, JIRA, GitHub, Slack and Quip.

Frontend Developer

At Vibe

December 2018 - March 2019

Vibe is a technology company specializing in delivering technology solutions that drive business digital transformation. The company manages software development projects, IT infrastructure management, information technology consultancy, integration, support and systems implementation for large public and private clients from various segments.

 Led a redesign of the UI architecture and layout of a legacy product with a modern frontend architecture developed with Angular and TypeScript, consuming web services built with Java Spring Boot.

- Participated in SCRUM daily meetings such as daily standups, sprint planning and retrospectives.
- Technologies/tools: AngularJS, JSF, Java, Oracle MySQL, ASP .NET, Jenkins, Azure, Slack, Trello,
 BitBucket.

Frontend Developer

At Acception

March 2018 - December 2018

Acception is a small fintech startup helping big Brazilian businesses to outsource their finance operations by building systems that manage invoicing experiences. The company provides software development, web and mobile applications services in financial products and incubator for startups.

- Defining the overall technical architecture for the UI applications projects.
- Engaging developers to use the appropriate design patterns and development practices and processes.
- Participated in SCRUM daily meetings such as daily standups, sprint planning and retrospectives.
- Technologies/tools: ReactJS, Groovy, JSF, Ionic, PostgreSQL, Jenkins, GitLab, Azure, Trello and Mantis.

Co-founder & Product Designer

At CastleDev

May 2016 - March 2018

Castle Dev was a Digital Agency startup which I co-founded in 2016 together with two partners. Our mission was to offer high-quality services for companies looking to build their digital presence online and manage technology to reach broader audiences and offer better products and services.

- Responsible for Product user experience, development and deployment of JAM Stack-based websites using Jekyll.
- Facilitated SCRUM daily meetings such as daily standups and retrospectives.
- Technologies/tools: Adobe XD, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Jekyll, CMS, Heroku, Trello, GitHub, MailChimp, Google Analytics and Google Docs.

Frontend Developer

At IT Proex - UFPA

Apr 2015 - March 2016

IT Proex fulfills the role of developing a University Extension Policy in order to deepen the discussion about extension as a social and university project vis-à-vis the government and public policies.

- Responsible for the UI layout of client-side web applications with JavaScript.
- Performed performance-optimization and cross-browser testing (IE 9+, Chrome, Firefox, Safari and Opera).
- Acted as a facilitator of Scrum ceremonies and daily meetings.
- Technologies/tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, MySQL Server, Git, Trello.

Software Developer Intern

At Equilibrium Web Apr 2013 - Apr 2014

Equilibrium Web is a small software development team that offer system management solutions to various industries such as Real Estate and Law.

- Responsible for the UI layout of client-side web applications with JavaScript.
- Responsible for creating functional, intuitive and responsive, cross-browser applications with JavaScript and PHP.
- Responsible for managing project documentation of company projects.
- Technologies/tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL Server, Git, Trello.

EDUCATION

GoStack Bootcamp

Rocketseat

Sep 2019 - Dec 2019

Fullstack JavaScript Development

Treehouse

Apr 2018 - Aug 2018

TOEFL - Score 99

ETS

2015 - 2017

Bachelor's Degree of Information Systems

UFPA (Federal University of Para)

Sep 2012 - Aug 2017

SIDE PROJECTS

Solo Engineer

Envelope

January 2020

Mail sending microservice built with Express.js, Docker and MongoDB.

Solo Engineer

L0ad

June 2019

L0ad is a simple toolkit for Load Testing HTTP servers. It uses Bash for scripting, Apache ab for benchmarking, CSV for data serialization and Gnuplot for plotting bar benchmarked data on bar charts.

Solo Engineer

JS Dev Tools

November 2017

A curated list of top open-source JavaScript libraries, frameworks and tools for developers.